PHINIC NYANGATE OGETO

LINKEDIN: https://www.linkedin.com/in/phinic-nyangate

EMAIL: phinicnyangate480@gmail.com PHONE NUMBER: +254796286466 GITHUB: https://github.com/phinic925

SUMMARY

Is a computer science graduate with a certification in software development with a two-year experience in the field. An industrious and dedicated young lady with passion in full stack development and excellent attitude towards work. I have learnt several languages/libraries and frameworks for experience to work in a fast growing company where I will use my skills such as javascript, react, ruby and ruby on rails to deliver best software development solutions.

SKILLS

- JavaScript
- React
- Ruby
- Ruby on rails
- PostgreSQL
- LAN/WAN Technologies
- Systems mantainance
- Wireless communication
- Routing protocols
- Subnetting

PROJECTS

E-farming application

This application allows farmers to upload their fresh products from the farm. They sell their products directly to the consumers. Users login to the app and search for a product of their choice and they purchase it from the farmer directly.

Recipe application

This application helps users search for various recipes of a particular ingredient. For instance one has an ingredient but has no idea of a meal to prepare with the ingredient this is where the application provides you with various meals to be prepared with that ingredient.

Job searching application

This is an application that helps employers to browse through jobseekers profiles available in the database and find their best match. This will reduce time wastage in recruitment process since employers will just search a jobseeker who matches their needs and make an offer. The application also allows jobseekers to register their profiles.

EXPERIENCE

Kenya power lighting company – ICT internship September 2021-december 2021

- Repairing hardware and software related issues.
- Fiber stringing, splicing and testing using splicing machine, power meter and OTDR
- Configuration, monitoring and troubleshooting of the SAP environment.
- Development of support procedures and strategies of systems, networks, operating systems and operating systems.

Jamii Telecommunications Limited- ICT internship

February 2023- july 2023

- Troubleshooting network
- Monitoring gpon architechture
- Provisioning new clients
- Solving clients network through crm
- Escalating tasks to tier2

EDUCATION

Kabarak University-Kenya

Bachelor in computer science *May 2018- Dec 2021*

Moringa School -Kenya

Certification software engineering *April 2022- Nov 2022*

Jomo kenyatta University- Kenya

Cisco Certified Network Associate February 2021- currently ongoing

REFEREES

Prof.Jackson Kitetu Dean School of Science Engineering and Technology P.O Private Bag 20157 KABARAK

Phone: 0721592737

Prof. Davies Kipkosgei Senior system administrator Kenya power

Phone: 0721405760

Lorna Koima

Jamii telecommunications

NOC support lead

Phone Number: 072566138

Email: lornakoima@gmail.com